A Guide to the Papers of Roberta Wellford, 1912-1927
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Roberta Wellford, 1912-1927
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6090
This collection consists of ca. 850 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The papers were a gift to the Library from Mrs. Sally Hamilton on July 4, 1959.
Scope and Content Information
This collection, 1912-1927, consists of ca. 850 items, including correspondence, speeches, printed, suffrage meeting minutes, and notebooks of the suffragist Roberta Wellford of Charlottesville, Virginia.
The correspondence documents Ms. Wellford's efforts to promote women suffrage through her work in the Equal Suffrage League from 1912 to 1920. It outlines her work as field director for the Virginia League of Women Voters and describes her participation on the National League's Committee on Reduction of Armaments, 1921-1922, and on the Committee of International Relations. Both the suffragist point-of-view and the actual activities of the women are detailed throughout the material. Information pertaining to the National Committee on the Christian Way of Life, 1923 to 1924, is also included.
Correspondents of interest include the following suffragists: Lila Meade Valentine, Alice O. Taylor, Ida M. Thompson, Elizabeth Lewis, Edith Clarke Cowles, Elizabeth Web Blakey, Anne Kern, Kate M. Gordon, Carrie Chapman Catt, Elizabeth J. Hauser, Pauline Okie, Winifred Branch Russell, and Adele Clark. Suffragists from Albemarle County are represented by Nancy Marshall and Evelyn Shaw.
Other correspondents include: Senators Thomas S. Martin and Claude Swanson, Congressmen J. W. Harrison and Andrew J. Montague, Governor Westmoreland Davis, attorney John Paull, and S. E. Nicholson of the National Council for Reduction of Armaments.
Contents List
- Equal Suffrage League of Virginia 1912-1915, 38 items (Box 1)
- Equal Suffrage League of Virginia 1916, 60 items. 2 folders. (Box 1)
- Equal Suffrage League of Virginia 1917, 78 items. 3 folders. (Box 1)
- Equal Suffrage League of Virginia 1918-1919, 30 items. (Box 1)
- Equal Suffrage League of Virginia and League of Women Voters 1920, 26 items (Box 1)
- Equal Suffrage League of Virginia and related n.d., 35 items (Box 1)
- League of Women Voters 1921, 250 items. 7 folders. (Box 1)
- League of Women Voters 1922, 60 items. 2 folders. (Box 2)
- League of Women Voters 1923, 26 items (Box 2)
- League of Women Voters 1924-1926, 36 items (Box 2)
- League of Women Voters: Printed and Stamps "Law--Not War" n.d., 20 items (Box 2)
- Minutes for Equal Suffrage League of Virginia and other meetings 1913-1916, n.d., 12 items (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous 1918, 1924, n.d., 14 items (Box 2)
- National Conference on the Christian Way of Life 1923, 8 items (Box 2)
- National Conference on the Christian Way of Life 1924, 18 items. (Box 2)
- Notes for Resolutions and Statements made by Roberta Wellford n.d., 35 items (Box 2)
- Notes for Speeches by Roberta Wellford ca. 1920, n.d., 70 items. 2 folders. (Box 2)
- Permanent Court of International Justice 1921-1924, n.d., 6 items. (Box 2)
- Photograph of a Medieval Pageant at the University of Virginia n.d., 1 item (Box 2)
- Southern Summer School for Women Workers in Industry at Sweet Briar, Virginia 1927, 7 items (Box 2)
- Women Suffrage 1913-1916, 14 items (Box 2)
- Calendar Diary/Daily Reminder belonging to Roberta Wellford 1921, Bound Volumes. 1 item (Box 3)
- Minutes of the Convention of the Equal Suffrage League of Virginia 1914 Nov, Bound Volumes. 1 item. (Box 3)
- Minutes of the Executive Council Meeting of November 12th and of the Convention of the Equal Suffrage League 1916-1917, Bound Volumes. 1 item (Box 3)
- Notes on First Aid n.d., Bound Volumes. 1 item (Box 3)
- Notes on the Peace Movement and Stabilization n.d., Bound Volumes. 1 item (Box 3)
- Notes on Political Science 1920, n.d., Bound Volumes. 2 items (Box 3)
- Notes on Procedures for Women to Vote, Women's Organizations, Women Suffrage, and Political Parties ca. 1921, Bound Volumes. 1 item (Box 3)